Hello everyone and welcome to English Mod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we're talking
a little bit about food
and about your health.
That's right today we're going to take a
look at our favorite maybe kind of food.
We're taking a look
at the fast food, all
these yummy but not
very healthy types of food.
Yeah we are so let's listen to our dialogue
and when we come back we'll be talking
about what some of these foods are and
what some of the phrases you've heard mean.
I'm hungry, let's order
up something to eat.
Okay maybe we can order a soup and a
salad from the restaurant down the street.
I was thinking of getting a
hamburger, fries and a chocolate sundae.
You eat too much junk
food. That sort of stuff clogs
up your arteries and is
very high in cholesterol.
Well I never seen the
gain weight so I don't mind.
It's not only about getting fat
or not, it's about being healthy.
You could really have some
health problems later on.
How about pizza, maybe some fried chicken,
better yet let's order some hot dogs.
You're a lost cause.
Alright we're back so now let's
take a look at language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So first up on language
takeaway is a very
unhealthy food it's
called a chocolate sundae.
That's right we wanted
to order hamburger,
french fries and a chocolate
sundae so chocolate
we know that this is the flavor that
comes from cocoa but what is a sundae?
Well basically a
sundae is a kind of ice
cream dessert, it comes
in a cup or a bowl and
it's usually vanilla ice
cream with chocolate
sauce and then
oftentimes a cherry on top.
So as you can see the
word is pronounced exactly
like the day sundae but it has
a different spelling in the end.
Yes you end, D-A-E sundae.
Right so this is a
chocolate sundae so when
you see this spelling a
sundae with an E that's
the dessert if you see it
with a Y and that's the day.
Exactly so chocolate
sundae actually a very
delicious dessert but
remember it's ice cream.
That's right now all
of these types of food,
hamburger, chocolate
sundae it's called junk
food, junk food, well
food you know, junk.
What is an example
of junk Marco?
Well something that's not
good or useful anymore so
maybe you have a trash that you need
to get rid of like an old TV, that's junk.
So my mom would always
say throw away this junk.
It's stuff that you don't need so junk
is things that you would throw away.
A junk food is the
kind of food that's not
healthy for you, it's the
food that you shouldn't
eat but it tends to
be really delicious.
That's right so for
example the hamburger,
french fries, a
chocolate sundae all this
would fall under this
category of junk food.
That's right and one of the things about
junk food is that it's high in cholesterol.
Now what is cholesterol Marco?
That's right so you
always have to be careful
your doctor says that
you shouldn't have
or you have to be careful about having high
cholesterol and that's just basically it's
a type of fat that is
found in animal products,
so for example beef
has cholesterol and
it's dangerous because it could
maybe cause health problems.
That's right so my friend needed to lower
his cholesterol and his doctor told him he
should eat less red meat, eat
more vegetables and fruits instead.
That's right so cholesterol is a you'll see
it all the time when you're shopping you'll
see that it's low in cholesterol or
no sugar or no calories stuff like that.
Exactly.
Now a food that
is very very high in
cholesterol is fried chicken
but it's also very delicious.
That's right fried
chicken now as you see
the first word there is fried and that
means that it was cooked in hot oil.
That's right and what's
important to remember
about most American
fried chicken is that
the chicken is usually put in a batter so
like a milk egg flour sauce and then it's
fried so on the outside it's
very very crispy and salty.
That's right so it's covered in like
a type of bread like a crispy bread.
Yeah that's right it's
it's usually very greasy
so when you eat it you have lots of grease
on your fingers but one of the reasons it
tastes so good is because as
you say Marco it's fried and oil.
That's right very
good so this is all the
vocab that we have for language takeaway
let's listen to the dialogue again.
I'm hungry let's order up something to eat.
Okay maybe we can order a soup and a
salad from the restaurant down the street.
I was thinking of getting a
hamburger fries and a chocolate sundae.
You eat too much junk food.
That sort of stuff clogs up your
arteries and is very high in cholesterol.
Well I never seen the
gain weight so I don't mind.
It's not only about getting fat
or not it's about being healthy.
You could really have some
health problems later on.
How about peaks there maybe some fried
chicken better yet let's order some hot dogs.
You're a lost cause.
All right now it's time for
some phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
So one of the first
phrases is actually
something that I'm excited
to talk about because
it comes up a lot in directions when
we're giving people directions somewhere.
So one of the people
in the dialogue said we
can order a soup and salad from
the restaurant down the street.
So this is you're
basically telling the person
where the restaurant
is and when you say
something is down the
street it means that it's nearby.
It is it's nearby it's
on the same street or
it's just you know it's just a few
minutes walk from where you are now.
Right right so you can say my apartment
is just down the street from this park.
So it's very close or you
could say I know him he
lived down the street from
me when we were children.
Wow okay so you live really
really close to you very good.
Now when we were
talking about junk food and
we were talking about
how it's not healthy
we said that junk food
clogs up your arteries.
All right a couple important
words here to clog up arteries
the verb to clog what does
that mean clog with the G?
It means it gets in
the way or obstructs it.
All right so for example
if a drain if I'm in my sink
if a drain is clogged the
water does not go down.
So the water starts
to build and build and
build and actually it's
very dangerous because
if it comes up too much
the water will go on the floor.
But that's a drain that's a
sink if you're talking about the
heart you would say that
cholesterol clogs up your arteries.
Right so your arteries are like these tubes
where blood passes and of course if they're
clogged up then blood
can't pass that's right
and if it's very serious
people sometimes
have to have a heart
surgery to clear those
arteries to take the the blockage
the clogging away from the arteries.
That's right that's
right okay so that is
to clog something up or
something is clogged up.
Now moving on when
we were giving suggestions
we said all right well
how about pizza or
maybe some fried chicken better
yet let's order some hot dogs.
All right now this is
a great phrase as you
say Marco for offering a suggestion you
could say I think we should eat hamburgers.
Better yet okay so what does
this mean this means I actually
had a better idea while I
was telling you my other idea.
So it can be used
in the middle of a
sentence like here right it's
kind of like an interjection.
Better yet you know what
let's let's get some pizza.
So it's better than the idea you just had.
So let's go swimming oh better yet let's go
play basketball right exactly now towards
the end our friend said
you know what your
lost cause what does
that mean what does this
phrase mean your lost cause you're a lost
cause it's an interesting phrase this is
basically a way of saying I
can do nothing to change you.
You have a bad habit or you have this bad
quality and anything I do it's not going
to help right so
something that is a lost
cause it means it's
hopeless helpless that's
right I cannot do
anything to change it okay
all right a lot of great vocab here
let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
I'm hungry let's order
up something to eat
okay maybe we can order a soup and the
salad from the restaurant down the street.
I was thinking of
getting a hamburger fries
and a chocolate sundae you eat too much
junk food that sort of stuff clogs up your
arteries and is very
high in cholesterol well
I never seen the gain
weight so I don't mind
it's not only about
getting fat or not it's
about being healthy you
could really have some
health problems later on
how about pizza maybe
some fried chicken better yet let's
order some hot dogs you're a lost cause.
Alright so talking
about junk food we took
a look at cholesterol
now apparently not all
cholesterol is bad
that's right there are two
kinds of cholesterol
HDLs and LDLs and one
kind is good for you and the other kind is
bad for you and so it's important when you
talk to your doctor you ask your doctor if
the bad cholesterol is high for you because
if it's the good
cholesterol that's high
you're probably not
going to experience health
problems but if you
have really high back
cholesterol then that's
something that you should
think about when you
eat and when you choose
the kinds of foods that
you eat right so usually
you know my doctor
always used to tell me to
not eat so many eggs
because eggs are high
in cholesterol that's right red meat and
eggs and salty foods I think but generally
speaking I think it's
good just to eat a lot
of vegetables and to
balance out your diet
so vegetables don't
really even have cholesterol
no they're low in
cholesterol and I think
they also have a lot of
vitamins and minerals
that your body
needs it's it's very very
interesting because
actually all food that is
usually very very delicious
is high in cholesterol
or high in calories
it's bad for you it's
basically junk food
yeah so potato chips hot
dogs pizza fried
chicken all these delicious
foods they're all
considered junk food and
they're all really bad
for you that's right
all right a very
interesting topic now there
are certain local
types of junk food that
people consider to be
junk food like for example
if you go maybe to
the middle east you'll
have the wraps right
that could be considered
a type of junk food I
guess yeah it's fast it's
greasy it is pretty
greasy all this delicious
like a shawarma wrap
exactly so maybe you
can let us know what
local type of junk food
you have this is mostly
American burgers fries
hot dogs exactly what
is it in your country
let us know our website is
englishpa.com we'll see you guys there bye